<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Batman on P.F. Hawkins</title>
    <link>http://pfhawkins.com/tags/batman/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Batman on P.F. Hawkins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 16:00:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pfhawkins.com/tags/batman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Sombriety</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/09/22/sombriety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2008 16:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/09/22/sombriety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re too funny.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why? What did I do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was laughing too hard to be taken aback. &amp;ldquo;What do you mean?&amp;rdquo; Snort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If I was &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; funny, then I wasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;just the right amount&lt;/em&gt; of funny. When
did I cross the line?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her hysterics subsided. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure.&amp;rdquo; She instinctively reached for his
hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I simply showed you the comic, which I thought was simply funny, and then
reiterated that I like the man in the last panel would be thinking about how
the bear might defend himself from&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She interrupted. &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t, you&amp;rsquo;ll kill it,&amp;rdquo; she said, her face drawing down into
a pout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But I thought I did kill it; I went too far.&amp;rdquo; He very nearly looked her full
in the face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now you have.&amp;rdquo; She actively avoided his stare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So I hadn&amp;rsquo;t before?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I was laughing my fool head off!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But you said I was &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; funny.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;God!&amp;rdquo; she blasphemed loudly enough for other passengers to hear. &amp;ldquo;Did you not
catch the emphasis you just repeated back to me? You&amp;rsquo;re too funny doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean
you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;excessively&lt;/em&gt; funny, just that I find you &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; funny.&amp;rdquo; She lightly
punched him in the should; he was oblivious to it. He was too busy thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh,&amp;rdquo; he said after a while. &amp;ldquo;I think I blew it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo; She was looking straight ahead. &amp;ldquo;Yes you did.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I suppose now isn&amp;rsquo;t the time to talk about marriage then.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I suppose not,&amp;rdquo; she said. &amp;ldquo;I thought we were going to have a nice discussion
about it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;On a bus? Because I showed you a comic strip?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why on earth must you always do this?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do what?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;One minute you&amp;rsquo;re hilarious and then you&amp;rsquo;re still huggable but then you&amp;rsquo;re
still so serious about everything it just&amp;hellip; you eat moments like zombies eat
brains.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unthinkingly?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She burst out laughing and whacked his chest with her purse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts on The Dark Knight</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/07/28/some-thoughts-on-the-dark-knight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2008 17:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/07/28/some-thoughts-on-the-dark-knight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went and saw the Dark Knight again. This time I went with my parents. My mom
is a pretty devout woman with a decent artistic sensibility. Afterward she was
still trying to process the experience, and it was good to get her take on
things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing she said that struck me: &amp;ldquo;Everyone says it&amp;rsquo;s lots darker than Batman
Begins. I hate that. It&amp;rsquo;s not dark, it&amp;rsquo;s sadistic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one sense, she&amp;rsquo;s right. It is sadistic. But the sense in which she&amp;rsquo;s right
is incomplete. The &lt;em&gt;Joker&lt;/em&gt; is sadistic, not the film. He is a twisted sadist
whose mere presence should have given the film an R rating. But the film
doesn&amp;rsquo;t glorify that evil, it &lt;em&gt;exposes&lt;/em&gt; it. It presents a glimmer of hope and
a dash of martyrdom in the face of such evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what evil it is. The Joker embodies depravity detached from sanity and
given free reign to deconstruct everything and everyone around him. And by
deconstruct, I mean either blow up or bring to despair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mom had another point: &amp;ldquo;Won&amp;rsquo;t portraying that evil push some people over
the edge?&amp;rdquo; Perhaps, but it is their choice to follow the siren song of evil.
The film is structured in such a way to make it clear that there are many and
profound negative consequences for allowing yourself to embrace that evil.
Two-face dies, spiritually in his rampage and then actually. Batman, by way of
contrast, has long ago learned to live with his grief and not succumb to the
temptations of despair. The contrast clearly highlights that the evil is not
to be trusted or embraced. Good clearly triumphs, to the extent that it can
given the horrific, 9-11 scale circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m considering catching a third screening, partly to let it sink in one more
time, and partly to see it in IMAX. And in choosing whether to, I do need to
take some of my mother&amp;rsquo;s concerns into account. Art does affect us,
powerfully, deeply, and there is a legitimate risk of responding improperly to
art. And such art should play only a minimal role in our lives. One of my
criticisms of the character of Father Ruiz-Sanchez in &lt;a href=&#34;h
ttp://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon
.com%2FCase-Conscience-Del-Rey-Impact%2Fdp%2F0345438353%3Fie%3DUTF8%26s%3Dbook
s%26qid%3D1217280480%26sr%3D8-1&amp;amp;tag=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creativ
e=9325&#34;&gt;A Case of Conscience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; is that
he didn&amp;rsquo;t read scripture or the divine office nearly as much as he read
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http
%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FFinnegans-Wake-Penguin-Modern-Classics%2Fdp%2F014118
311X%3Fie%3DUTF8%26s%3Dbooks%26qid%3D1217280878%26sr%3D8-1&amp;amp;tag=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;lin
kCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&#34;&gt;Finnegan&amp;rsquo;s Wake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.assoc-
amazon.com/e/ir?t=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;l=ur2&amp;amp;o=1&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;. Art was taking up an unhealthy chunk
of his life, likely because he gave himself over to some aspects of the work
that he responded wrongly to. But the work &lt;em&gt;as a whole&lt;/em&gt; needs to be
considered, not just the villain. And you can&amp;rsquo;t allow a work of art to push
you over the edge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>