<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thought on P.F. Hawkins</title>
    <link>http://pfhawkins.com/categories/thought/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thought on P.F. Hawkins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pfhawkins.com/categories/thought/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Mundanities Behind the Curtain</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2011/12/18/mundanities-behind-the-curtain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2011/12/18/mundanities-behind-the-curtain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is no story of consequence to this. I tire of using &lt;a href=&#34;wordpress.org&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt;. I deal with it at work and it wearies me. So I am trying something new here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next iteration of the blog employs &lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org&#34;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt;. I may have to update the colophon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hawkins&#39; Law</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2011/09/22/hawkins-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 16:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2011/09/22/hawkins-law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The office VPN works excellently, except right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing ihopesolution.com</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2009/07/07/announcing-ihopesolutioncom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 10:24:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2009/07/07/announcing-ihopesolutioncom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So a &lt;a href=&#34;http://hoobajoobfaq.org&#34;&gt;sysadmin friend&lt;/a&gt; and I decided that there just
weren&amp;rsquo;t enough blogs about systems administration and linux out there. So we
started another one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ihopesolution.com&#34;&gt;ihopesolution.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure it will develop its own voice, since we both have, um, firmly held
opinions about how things should be done. And odd senses of humor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I tend to use emacs more for writing and org-mode rather than
sysadminning, I&amp;rsquo;ll keep my emacs posts for my personal blog. (And so ends my
feeble attempt to justify tagging this &amp;ldquo;emacs&amp;rdquo; and watching it hit planet
emacsen.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Lending</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/08/30/book-lending/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2008 09:23:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/08/30/book-lending/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a new theory of book-lending. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been extremely recalcitrant
to lend out my precious, precious tomes. They are my babies. Letting someone
else read them who certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t appreciate them to the same degree, or in
the same kind, is a risky proposition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current reading pile includes a heaping helping of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Austrian_economics&#34;&gt;Austrian
Economics&lt;/a&gt;. I love this
stuff. A sense of economics on this scale rewires your brain circuitry (what a
crappy, ubiquitous brain-as-turing-machine metaphor) in subtle and not so
subtle ways. It is some of the best non-fiction reading I&amp;rsquo;ve engaged in in
years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to lend these books out. I simply must. I&amp;rsquo;ve attempted to get others
interested in them, with a little success. My brother, who is reliabel in
returning books I&amp;rsquo;ve lent him unread, raved about Ron Paul&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2
F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FRevolution-Manifesto-Ron-Paul%2Fdp%2F0446537519%3Fie%3DUT
F8%26s%3Dbooks%26qid%3D1220101874%26sr%3D8-1&amp;amp;tag=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp
=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&#34;&gt;The Revolution:
A Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;, which got me started on this kick. I&amp;rsquo;ll next lend him
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;locat
ion=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FEconomics-One-Lesson-Shortest-Understand%2Fd
p%2F0517548232%3Fie%3DUTF8%26s%3Dbooks%26qid%3D1220102088%26sr%3D8-1&amp;amp;tag=phawk
com-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&#34;&gt;Economics in One Lesson&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_Hazlitt&#34;&gt;Henry
Hazlitt&lt;/a&gt;. And I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten better
about lending out other sacred cows; after the Watchmen trailer hit the web I
lent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A
%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FWatchmen-Alan-Moore%2Fdp%2F0930289234%3Fie%3DUTF8%26s%3
Dbooks%26qid%3D1220102292%26sr%3D8-1&amp;amp;tag=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;cr
eative=9325&#34;&gt;my copy&lt;/a&gt; to a friend at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The realization, which has been slow in coming, dawns that I&amp;rsquo;ve read book X
once, and the odds of me rereading it in the next few years are pretty slim. I
can, therefore, safely risk the copy into the hand of others, where they can
better and more frequently fulfill their functions as books. A book is at its
best when its being read, when a man is bending his soul to the shape of
another&amp;rsquo;s thought. The more capital I can pump into the marketplace of
thought, the better served the consumers of that capital; not humanity, but
flesh-and-blood humans. I&amp;rsquo;ve a couple books, mostly reference, that others can
read only in the confines of my abode, but they are now the exception rather
than the rule.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stupid Simple Bibsonomy to Delicious Migration</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/08/11/stupid-simple-bibsonomy-to-delicious-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 11:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/08/11/stupid-simple-bibsonomy-to-delicious-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back I switched from &lt;a href=&#34;http://delicious.com&#34;&gt;delicious&lt;/a&gt; to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bibsonomy.org&#34;&gt;bibsonomy&lt;/a&gt; to handle all my social bookmarking needs. I
was all taken in by the RDF backing. I decided recently to switch back, since
it didn&amp;rsquo;t have the user base and general ecosystem, it&amp;rsquo;s geared toward more
academic pursuits, and RDF isn&amp;rsquo;t all it&amp;rsquo;s cracked up to be. Here&amp;rsquo;s a tarball
of the scripts I used to move the bookmarks back into delicious:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&#34;http://pfhawkins.com/bib2del.tgz&#34;&gt;bib2del&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caveats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bibsonomy handles unicode characters, delicious doesn&amp;rsquo;t. I opted to delete/edit the few bibsonomy bookmarks that were giving me those errors, but it will error out when you pass delicious a title with a smart apostrophe, smart quotes, em-dash, or other non-ascii character.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a dumb script. It will take all your bibsonomy bookmarks and add them one by one, with a 1.1 second delay in between to keep delicious happy. If, for some reason, you pass delicious a unicode character and it errors out, it will attempt to readd all the bookmarks you successfully added the last go round.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will need to ask bibsonomy nicely for a developer&amp;rsquo;s api key. delicious only needs username and password.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have written something that stored the bibsonomy bookmarks locally,
cleaned up the unicode, and then pushed everything to delicious, but this does
99% of what I wanted it to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to give a shout-out to two fabulous webservices that allow RESTful
api access to the information they store on my behalf, and to those brave
souls who wrote python bindings to those apis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. Not only does delicious choke on unicode, but it stores tags as space-
delimited strings. Strings! Boggles the mind, it does.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I don’t want to end up like this</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/10/03/i-dont-want-to-end-up-like-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2007 12:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/10/03/i-dont-want-to-end-up-like-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I previously mentioned that I was working on my own custom blog software for
this site. I&amp;rsquo;m not posting as I do so, because if I did, I&amp;rsquo;d end up with
something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ftrain.com/archive_ftrainone_919746918.html&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.
And you don&amp;rsquo;t want to read that, do you?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suckage</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/09/19/suckage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2007 06:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/09/19/suckage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The only to write well is to write often and get the kinks out. I don&amp;rsquo;t write
well yet. Therefore, expect to see a fair deal of suckage in this space before
you start to see amazing prose of stunning brilliance. (And then, thank God
that you&amp;rsquo;re only seeing a fraction of what I&amp;rsquo;m actually writing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have been warned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decisions, decisions</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/09/14/decisions-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2007 07:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/09/14/decisions-decisions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not just being quiet here, dear hypothetical reader; I&amp;rsquo;m sitting on a
couple of posts, waiting for the perfect time to post them. I realize that
they are going unread just sitting on my hard drive. It&amp;rsquo;s just that I&amp;rsquo;m not
confident that they are any good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the posts is the first in a series of posts on authors who choose to
utilize their first and middle initials in public, rather than their full
names. (Thanks to the reality of domain names, and the fact that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patrickhawkins.net&#34;&gt;some
organist&lt;/a&gt; beat me to it, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to go
down this route as well.) Interesting concept for a series, or a complete dud?
Who knows until I actually post?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the first post in that series I&amp;rsquo;ve written, on G.K. Chesterton, blows.
Well, it&amp;rsquo;s not horrible, but it has no zest. Which, for a post on someone as
witty as Chesterton, is inexcusable. It&amp;rsquo;s got the one funny anecdote, but I&amp;rsquo;m
still not sure about the whole format for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other post I&amp;rsquo;m sitting on is another review, on another science fiction
novel to which I had another &amp;ldquo;meh&amp;rdquo; reaction. It was simply blah. And is that
really worth letting the whole world know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-other-distraction&#34;&gt;The Other Distraction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My other distraction is trying to start learning
&lt;a href=&#34;http://djangoproject.com&#34;&gt;django&lt;/a&gt; so I can write my own content management
system that not only keeps track of what I publish to this site but also as
much information as possible on books I&amp;rsquo;ve read, as well as tracking the books
I own. I want an insanely detailed database of what books I&amp;rsquo;ve read, which
ones I own, perhaps a mini-review or mini-impression of every single one, an
easy-for-me system for gathering that information all in one place and setting
down to write a review. But time I work on that is time I&amp;rsquo;m not writing
something for the website as it is. Which is wordpress. And I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I
want to get addicted to some wordpress features that I&amp;rsquo;ll have to take much
time, as well as wailing and gnashing of teeth, to properly re-implement in my
custom django solution. Icky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-third-distraction&#34;&gt;The Third Distraction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings us to the little matter of hey, pf, if you&amp;rsquo;re working on this
website as much as it sounds like, are you actually writing any fiction like
you promised yourself? To which I would say, &amp;ldquo;Hah! Of course not.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m not
writing more than a few hundred words a week, which would get you a short
story a quarter after revising. Not a good schedule. I need to amp up my
output. Big time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finally&#34;&gt;Finally&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good thing about having a personal website is that you can whine as much
as you want. Whine whine whine!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extramundane</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/08/22/extramundane/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 13:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/08/22/extramundane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was going through &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0684857618?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;
linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0684857618&#34;&gt;The Word Museum: The Most Remarkable English Words Ever F
orgotten&lt;/a&gt; and I found this
complete gem of a word:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extramundane: the infinite empty space, which is by some supposed to be
extended beyond the bounds of the universe, and in which there is nothing at
all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is very near what I would call a perfect word. As is this other one I
found:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stellascript: That which is written in the stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to write stellascript when I grow up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/08/11/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2007 09:58:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/08/11/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to pfhawkins.com!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is P.F. Hawkins. I have a first name and a middle name of which I am
not ashamed (unlike Clive Staples Lewis or Pelham Grenville Wodehouse), but my
first name/last name combination was not available as a domain name, so I
thought I would imitate them in using my first two initials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided whether or not I am going to use this site as a serious,
work-related sort of site for freelancing (I might start copywriting on the
side), or if I&amp;rsquo;m going to ignore all that and go with my life-long dream of
becoming a published novelist. Probably the latter. Hopefully after doing this
for a few months, the site will take on a life of its own. But in the
meantime, feel free to stick around and watch me thrash about whilst I find my
voice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>