<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on P.F. Hawkins</title>
    <link>http://pfhawkins.com/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on P.F. Hawkins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 10:48:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pfhawkins.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>On Finding a Document Production Workflow for Emacs</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2009/01/19/on-finding-a-document-production-workflow-for-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 10:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2009/01/19/on-finding-a-document-production-workflow-for-emacs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a modest goal: write some fiction. Instead of actually working toward
accomplishing that goal, I&amp;rsquo;m going to obsess about the toolchain and other
externalities used to support this endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will use revision control. By an accident of history I will be using git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will use a text editor. Since I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to run into frictions
from modal editing while fiction writing, I will be using Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If fictions were primarily distributed and displayed as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gutenberg.org/catalog/&#34;&gt;plain-text
files&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;d be good to go. They aren&amp;rsquo;t, and
I would like to at least attempt to send this higher up the food chain, ending
in either a Microsoft Word Document or PDF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say, LaTeX makes some nice pdfs. While it manifestly does not suck, and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/software/auctex/&#34;&gt;AucTeX&lt;/a&gt; is the bee&amp;rsquo;s knees, I want to do
whatever I can in the way of premature optimization to tilt the ratio of
writing to formatting heavily in writing&amp;rsquo;s favor. LaTeX is formatting heavy,
so I&amp;rsquo;d like to avoid that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docbook XML also suffers from the same issue. It is a well-specced and quite
nice document format. And while &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/NxmlMode&#34;&gt;nxml-
mode&lt;/a&gt; is bar-none the premier way to
edit straight XML, sorry, it ain&amp;rsquo;t happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what essentially plain-text formats can I convert to either LaTeX or
Docbook XML, which I can then use to produce my output format of choice? As of
this writing, I see three viable options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://orgmode.org/&#34;&gt;org-mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mwolson.org/projects/EmacsMuse.html&#34;&gt;muse-mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://markdown.infogami.com/&#34;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://johnmacfarlane.net/pandoc/&#34;&gt;pandoc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;org-mode ships with emacs, and is great. Writing novels in it would be
orthogonal to its original purpose in note-taking and agenda-organizing. It
only exports LaTeX/PDF, not Docbook. While it may work, I think successive
options are more promising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;muse-mode is designed from the ground up for publishing, not note-taking. It
exports both LaTeX and Docbook. This would probably be my first choice, except
for one thing: its wiki syntax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems asinine of me to start complaining about a wiki syntax now. I mean,
isn&amp;rsquo;t that the whole point of this exercise, to find a wiki-like syntax I can
convert from? Right. I&amp;rsquo;m not complaining about &lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt; wiki syntax, I&amp;rsquo;m
complaining about &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; wiki syntax. All in all it&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily a bad
one, but it is a domain-specific language for this mode only. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.wired.com/monkeybites/2008/05/a-million-littl.html&#34;&gt;It enjoys no
reuse outside of this particular
application.&lt;/a&gt;
If the third option didn&amp;rsquo;t exist, I&amp;rsquo;d probably use it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we have markdown, and the magical frobnicator that frobnicates markdown
into a potpourri of other formats: namely, pandoc. &lt;a href=&#34;http://jblevins.org/projects/markdown-mode/&#34;&gt;Markdown
mode&lt;/a&gt; is pretty handy, and I&amp;rsquo;ll
probably end up writing a simple minor-mode or git-hook bash script for
automating the pandoc conversions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll let you know how this turns out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts Writers Have</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/05/11/thoughts-writers-have/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2008 03:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/05/11/thoughts-writers-have/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I could really go for a smoke. I&amp;rsquo;m a non-smoker. The most I ever smoked was
three times in one kinda stressful week in college. And I try to buy the good
stuff when I do. No Camels for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I ever want a smoke, it&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;ve an itch that needs scratching, and a
cigarette seems like the shortest path to itch relief. It never is though.
There&amp;rsquo;s a deeper underlying reason why I have dry skin. The itching won&amp;rsquo;t
abate until I eat my vitamins, or eat animal fats, or stop eating melons, or
get new genes. The rest is vapid style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s so much style to smoking. Nowadays it happens outside. Always with the
lighting it, holding it in your fingers, sucking on it, occasionally looking
at it. It&amp;rsquo;s the perfect excuse to take a break, because who would deny an
itching man his scratch? And it can&amp;rsquo;t be done indoors. So it becomes a
paradigm shift. An opportunity for a moment. With friends, huddled against the
cold and the itch. Or alone with the itch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s that kind of moment, and then there&amp;rsquo;s mortal peril. That innocent
girl, tied against the tracks, kicking her petticoat. The mustachioed man
behind the bushes, twirling his handlebar with growing glee as his dastardly
design is about to bear fruit. And our clean, upright protagonist, whose white
teeth shine brightly in his favor as he strains against inconceivable odds to
ride his worthy steed to the rails in time to throw the switch, sending the
train on a different path, the one without a buxom beauty. The thrall of
potential defeat in the moments before improbable success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catharsis. You can relax now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In those moments, either smoking or rescuing a blossom of virginity from the
jaws of death, in these moments are birthed a potential writer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no such thing as a Greek muse, but there is such a thing as a moment.
Live through enough successive ones with a tolerably observant eye, and one
will feel, think, experience. And that will either need to be processed or
dismissed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing about it can scratch that itch. But the root cause will be here until
judgment day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Use Emacs</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/10/15/how-i-use-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2007 16:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/10/15/how-i-use-emacs/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When I started using Emacs, I had grandiose notions of producing copious
amounts of prose, linking it together in all sorts of interesting and helpful
ways, and basically revolutionizing the way I experienced computers. But most
of all, I had a new and urgent desire to do everything from the keyboard in a
blazingly efficient manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I proceeded to burn the Emacs keybindings into my brain and fingers. I
developed some slightly inefficient workflows (copying and pasting from text
documents into OpenOffice documents, editing the original text file based on
whatever page length I was going for, rinse and repeat until paper is
produced) that were, on the whole, a net gain due to the speed of typing
without mousing. The linux filesystem positively danced under my fingertips. I
had more control over my system than I had ever had on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I progressed to producing documents and drafts in LaTeX. While it&amp;rsquo;s a bit
arcane, using Emacs with AUCTeX made writing LaTeX arguably faster (and
certainly prettier) than writing in Microsoft Word. My long-held desire,
though, was to &lt;em&gt;learn a programming language&lt;/em&gt; (I chose python) and &lt;em&gt;code my
own Content Management System&lt;/em&gt;. Events in meatspace have conspired against me
acheiving that goal up to this point; now I am making progress. I can&amp;rsquo;t
imagine working in any other editor. Oh wait: I can. I switched to vim for
four months earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yes-i-tried-vim:a832e82fbc16a5dad69526e9113f29d5&#34;&gt;Yes, I tried Vim&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You heard me: I tried vim. My main motivation was a bout of Emacs Pinky. My
left pinky occasionally gets sore if I spend too much time on the laptop. At
the time I attributed it to the control sequences that Emacs uses, but now I&amp;rsquo;m
more aware that it&amp;rsquo;s just that my laptop has an inelegant and potentially
harmful keyboard. If I use an ergonomic keyboard with Emacs, I&amp;rsquo;m fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vim was fine. It&amp;rsquo;s a great text editor. If you want a powerful text editor,
your two choices are vim and Emacs, and though I prefer Emacs, I won&amp;rsquo;t fault
you for choosing vim. It does some fantabulous things. You can script it in
python, for example. But scripting vim in python feels a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; like
scripting Emacs in python; there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of cruft, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t play well
with the innards of the system like elisp does. And there were all these
little things that I missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-m-doing-with-emacs-now:a832e82fbc16a5dad69526e9113f29d5&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m Doing With Emacs Now&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m evolving into the type of person who tries to do as much as possible
inside Emacs. Here&amp;rsquo;s a partial list of how I use it now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal Planner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding environment for my as-yet-unfinished CMS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing Fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;irc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;limited web browsing (mostly online APIs for the python libraries I&amp;rsquo;m investigating)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World Domination
Okay, I really haven&amp;rsquo;t used Emacs for world domination yet. But as I was
reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0812579844?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;t
ag=phawkcom-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0812579844&#34;&gt;The Golden Age&lt;/a&gt;,
I was slightly disappointed when he was naming some of the far-future self-
aware AI characters, and Emacs didn&amp;rsquo;t make the list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>