<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linguistics on P.F. Hawkins</title>
    <link>http://pfhawkins.com/tags/linguistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linguistics on P.F. Hawkins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 10:09:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pfhawkins.com/tags/linguistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Undead</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/09/02/undead/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 10:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2008/09/02/undead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Un-&amp;rdquo; is a negative prefix denoting the opposite of the word to which it is
affixed. The nearest equivalent prefix is &amp;ldquo;non-&amp;rdquo;, which denotes the same
thing. &amp;ldquo;Un-&amp;rdquo;, however, also possesses a connotation (in many applications of
the prefix) of time, where previously the state or thing that is not, once
was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of zombies, the term &amp;ldquo;undead&amp;rdquo; is used to refer to them as a
collective whole, as a race or species. &amp;ldquo;Nondead&amp;rdquo; is less appropriate, for
while it would convey the fact that zombies are far more ambulatory than the
normative deceased, it fails to convey that the zombies were once dead; or, if
it does convey that, it does so with much less force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Another example of this connotation, although one based in marketing rather
than in organic etymology, holds for &amp;ldquo;uncola&amp;rdquo;; 7up has always been a
carbonated sweet water, and therefore &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; cola, although it subverts the usual
formulae for what is deemed as cola, and in so doing is perceived [due to
intensive advertising more than anything] as having progressed from a state of
being cola to a state of being &lt;strong&gt;beyond&lt;/strong&gt; cola.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The utility of the &amp;ldquo;un-&amp;rdquo; prefix used in this manner cannot be overstated. For
clearly, the undead, while no longer deceased, also are no longer living. The
simple addition of this prefix drums up a word for a third state of being.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>