<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web on P.F. Hawkins</title>
    <link>http://pfhawkins.com/tags/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web on P.F. Hawkins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 11:25:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pfhawkins.com/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Came to Love Emacs</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/10/10/how-i-came-to-love-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 11:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2007/10/10/how-i-came-to-love-emacs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the story of a man and his favorite text editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2001, I was a freshman in college, which meant the closest thing to
highspeed internet that I had hitherto experienced. Which upped my time
surfing the web. One of the delightful sites I lighted upon was
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ftrain.com&#34;&gt;Ftrain.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, I dug through Ftrain&amp;rsquo;s archives and found &lt;a href=&#34;http://ftrain.com/util_emacs_hints.html&#34;&gt;Emacs
Notepad&lt;/a&gt;. I was intrigued. Having
exclusively used Word (and Notepad to edit HTML - ha!) up until that point,
this Emacs thingy sounded fascinating. I downloaded a Windows version right
away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I soon found that the Windows port of Emacs was stuck on version 19, and the
rest of the Emacs-lovin&amp;rsquo; universe was using version 21 on some posix-compliant
operating system. I decided to hope and pray that soon the Emacs developers
would take a little time out to help us poor souls using Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a long wait. A long wait in which &lt;em&gt;I could not get LaTeX to work&lt;/em&gt;. So
long, in fact, that the next fall, with the aid of a new dorm-mate, I dual-
booted Red Hat 9 Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s great about Emacs, and about free software in general, is that I have
as much control as I desire over my computer. I haven&amp;rsquo;t taken the time to
install Linux from scratch, but if I wanted to, the tools are there, and there
aren&amp;rsquo;t any proprietary hindrances or DRM snafus to thwart my progress. My
limited ability to understand maths may hinder me, but my software isn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So actually, I am indebted to Emacs for not only making my computing life much
easier and more productive, but from freeing me from the limitations of
Microsoft. Although I see I didn&amp;rsquo;t really describe just how it has made my
computing life easier, or more productive. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to remedy that in a
future post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DISCLAIMER: I never said it was a good story of a man and his favorite text
editor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>