<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Markdown on P.F. Hawkins</title>
    <link>http://pfhawkins.com/tags/markdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Markdown on P.F. Hawkins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 10:48:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pfhawkins.com/tags/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>On Finding a Document Production Workflow for Emacs</title>
      <link>http://pfhawkins.com/2009/01/19/on-finding-a-document-production-workflow-for-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 10:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pfhawkins.com/2009/01/19/on-finding-a-document-production-workflow-for-emacs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a modest goal: write some fiction. Instead of actually working toward
accomplishing that goal, I&amp;rsquo;m going to obsess about the toolchain and other
externalities used to support this endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will use revision control. By an accident of history I will be using git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will use a text editor. Since I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to run into frictions
from modal editing while fiction writing, I will be using Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If fictions were primarily distributed and displayed as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gutenberg.org/catalog/&#34;&gt;plain-text
files&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;d be good to go. They aren&amp;rsquo;t, and
I would like to at least attempt to send this higher up the food chain, ending
in either a Microsoft Word Document or PDF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say, LaTeX makes some nice pdfs. While it manifestly does not suck, and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/software/auctex/&#34;&gt;AucTeX&lt;/a&gt; is the bee&amp;rsquo;s knees, I want to do
whatever I can in the way of premature optimization to tilt the ratio of
writing to formatting heavily in writing&amp;rsquo;s favor. LaTeX is formatting heavy,
so I&amp;rsquo;d like to avoid that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Docbook XML also suffers from the same issue. It is a well-specced and quite
nice document format. And while &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emacswiki.org/emacs/NxmlMode&#34;&gt;nxml-
mode&lt;/a&gt; is bar-none the premier way to
edit straight XML, sorry, it ain&amp;rsquo;t happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what essentially plain-text formats can I convert to either LaTeX or
Docbook XML, which I can then use to produce my output format of choice? As of
this writing, I see three viable options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://orgmode.org/&#34;&gt;org-mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mwolson.org/projects/EmacsMuse.html&#34;&gt;muse-mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://markdown.infogami.com/&#34;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://johnmacfarlane.net/pandoc/&#34;&gt;pandoc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;org-mode ships with emacs, and is great. Writing novels in it would be
orthogonal to its original purpose in note-taking and agenda-organizing. It
only exports LaTeX/PDF, not Docbook. While it may work, I think successive
options are more promising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;muse-mode is designed from the ground up for publishing, not note-taking. It
exports both LaTeX and Docbook. This would probably be my first choice, except
for one thing: its wiki syntax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems asinine of me to start complaining about a wiki syntax now. I mean,
isn&amp;rsquo;t that the whole point of this exercise, to find a wiki-like syntax I can
convert from? Right. I&amp;rsquo;m not complaining about &lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt; wiki syntax, I&amp;rsquo;m
complaining about &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; wiki syntax. All in all it&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily a bad
one, but it is a domain-specific language for this mode only. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.wired.com/monkeybites/2008/05/a-million-littl.html&#34;&gt;It enjoys no
reuse outside of this particular
application.&lt;/a&gt;
If the third option didn&amp;rsquo;t exist, I&amp;rsquo;d probably use it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we have markdown, and the magical frobnicator that frobnicates markdown
into a potpourri of other formats: namely, pandoc. &lt;a href=&#34;http://jblevins.org/projects/markdown-mode/&#34;&gt;Markdown
mode&lt;/a&gt; is pretty handy, and I&amp;rsquo;ll
probably end up writing a simple minor-mode or git-hook bash script for
automating the pandoc conversions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll let you know how this turns out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>